Okay, we've got just a few more people coming in please be sure to fill out
...evaluation the session if you love court on as much as we do
be sure to do it if you're not so...about...on a grab a cup of coffee
...walk funny time...
All right.
So, for today...going to talk about core...extensibility I'm
...open by saying thank you it's extraordinarily hard can be with a beautiful sunny day
and san francisco so thank you very much for coming inside and spending
...time with us today what's amazing to me is that we just introduced core
...into the world only about a year-ago and
it's been a pretty amazing year we spent that time doubling down our technology to make
or more capable better for the consumer we spend a ton of time
...consumers to understand what are the most important things core tonic
...but most interestingly I've been spending a ton of time with
developers and partners to figure out how together we can create value for the
customer in fact I've travelled around the world this year meeting
with developers just like you to talk about what core tonic...do
so that together we make the customer even happier so today I'm going to talk about
the two big questions that came out of those discussions first we know core
...really rapidly evolving what's that product...turn into so we can figure out of
it makes sense to integrate with core...and second frankly what can court on a
...for developers and partners what value can
she provide you so that's what we're going to talk about today my name is
...planning for core tang I'm here with my friend...amounting and we're going to spend
the next sixty-minutes talking specifically about the questions that
you've asked us and hopefully at the end of that time you're going to leave here with
a really good understanding of the products and really useful tangible tools you can
use to integrate into core time...that looks like.
The beginning I'm going to focus on what is
core time specifically what's the vision for the product where she
...go over the next couple years and what value she creates for developers
that I'm going to switch over to...and he's going to dyed strata and talk about what
are the specific things you can do today to create value with core
...for your applications to complete tasks and really get
to things quickly so that's our goal will save a little bit of time at the end for
some q and a because we want this conversation to be
ongoing we think the best products come from partnerships so
we want to continue to me with you and continue to evolve this product
let's jump right in I remember the first day when we started core time we
...the table and we talked about what made a really good personal assistant we
looked at real-world examples?
And, what we found?
Networks.
This is cool I can do a rock star thing and stand in front of the big speaker.
What we found was really great personal systems had
to key characteristics one they knew the client better than anybody
and to the help them get things done so we made massive investments
and personalization and task completion good assistance
...to work with an easy to talk to so we've really focused on
natural language with your typing...talking it's really easy to interact with core
tonic and as you've heard now we're integrating charts core tonic into windows ten which means
protons going to be available to millions and millions and
millions of users across a broad set of devices and on
those devices should be able to bring you what you need across search device your
personal cloud so we've got a great start but it's just a start?
And, started something really interesting because the way I
think about it it's not just there's millions and millions of users it's not just that
there's more devices and they're more capable than ever
it's that how we interact with devices is changing.
Right member in the beginning we want...the device we
...a command line some of a still do and then eventually we use the mouse.
And, then eventually we got other devices we use touch.
And, now we're evolving into a new way to interact devices
that's much more natural it's much more contextual and that's
...is really about how do we connect people with the experiences on
their devices that they value most in the most natural contextual
easy and engaging way and that's
actually an opportunity she creates for developers what
is that look like if I give you a sneak peek of how we're talking about core tama with
consumers this is just...adding put together give you a sense of at the time we
...consumers what they've told this is a really good personal assistant makes you feel like the
hero of your own life you can get anything done it's all going great and that's what
core...as about that when you look at those real personal
assistance?
They don't do it on their own do they they're smart they're capable they can get
things done but the hallmark of a great personal assistant is they have this
network of experts your concierge...you a great place to go to dinner
because he knows which restaurant...call-in who to talk to your personal system can help you get your
car fixed because she knows which garage in which mechanic can get that done
...the same she wants to know the experts that are important
to the customer and in this world the experts are you.
She wants to be able to connect the customer in the most natural
and compelling way to you because you're the experts of what you do
and that's the opportunity we want to talk about today now let's...that looks like
...windows...the beautiful thing about core time
she's right there I'm showing example from a pc issues
...on the desktop and she's ready to greet you at the sound of your voice
at the touch of your hand the click your mouse
...there it's not their generically she's there specifically
for you she knows what's going on with your life what we've learned is the
more person why she gets the more engaging that she is
...that personalization also creates
a new opportunity when we talk to real personal assistance we found
a lot of them kept notebooks on their boss literally these were paper bound notebooks
...write down this is what he likes this is what he doesn't like this the
stuff he says he doesn't like
...secretly likes and they keep track of all that stuff well so this core
tanaka photon has a notebook and in
...notebook she keeps track of the things that are important
customer really big things like hey this is when you want to
breach out and talk to them and this is when he wants to be left alone so you're not
noisier disturbing people these this is what's happening is...these are the sports teams
is interested in here's the music he likes here's the places he likes to go here's what's
happening in his world.
And, consumers love that because it actually makes that
much more personal the opportunity for developers is that means core
...knows when to reach out to someone with the right content at
the right time on the right device in the right way
you're cutting through the clutter and...reaching the customer
very natural useful and compelling way.
What does that look like unsure if you examples these are examples from windows ten
from the far-left she can reach our proactively writing a really good assistant
wouldn't be sitting at their desk just staring off into space right when you saw them they walk up and
greet you and say here's stuff that you need to know protons the same way here what score here's what's going on
...your life she can proactively reach you but just like
a good assistant chicken tournament dime and go get you what you need so she can get it from the
web...get it from your neighborhood and displayed in a really beautiful way autonomy
proactively and re actively drives an ongoing dialogue with the
customer now it's more than just answering questions it's about getting
things done so she can do a broad variety of things she can help you with your
device she can help...your real-world this is what you need to do at this time or
this place so your life goes better but the thing that I'm most excited about is
she can connect you with those applications she can help you with the experiences that
are most important to you now we know even in the early days that is
...there's right now for core tanaka she's helping
consumers do twenty million high-value...tasks a month?
And, that's only going to grow.
With windows time because again you've got millions and millions
and millions of users across all those devices so the opportunity for
us today is if you have this deeply personal digital
...really easy to interact with his building this ongoing conversation and she
can connect consumers in the right way with
your applications how do we do it so...let's talk about how we get that done.
Other...today unfunded build
great so I'm super excited to be here today to talk to-you about protonextensibility and
what you can do in windows ten a little bit about what's new and how you can take advantage of
...capabilities so, specifically
...going to be talking about three big areas deep linking from...to your
...scenarios so, if you think about...she's
...the product provides a very simple intuitive natural way to
interact with your computer for users so one of the areas...is to help you deep
...from proton leverage that experience through to your experiences so
...getting the benefits of that simple natural interface through to your apps the second area we're going to talk
about is completing tasks directly inside...we have some it really
exciting announcements to share with you today some new product capabilities and apis to share with you today so,
if you really if you think about is I was saying that...is really good at
completing tasks for people things like setting appointments setting reminders you know,
sending e-mail sending messages were enabling we're opening up parts of that framework to allow
you to integrate your tasks for your apps directly with an
...on I'm going to show you how to do that and the third
we're going to touch ontalk about is finding information quickly so core...has a vast
...powered through public information right but what about when you want when you have your
own data that you want to use to help your user base
get access to very quickly we're going to talk about how ways that you can connect
court on a to that private information to your own datasets and,
look, for that and give quick access to users to that information?
Let's talk about depleting first.
So, today we're announcing voice commands for the universal windows, windows
out platform if you're familiar with this feature this was something we had available on phone eight-point one
bringing that...to the universe...platform today the sdk that you can
go download right now has this capability we have a number of samples and the and
...give you some pointers and links to go download those the idea here for those are not familiar with it is the apps
can effectively register for commands they can author a certain structure command that they want
users to be able to say to...honor to have them invoked with context and,
look, at some examples and some demos of that really quick pretty soon and,
this is available for...and javascript apps?
Let's take a look at the architectural...to give you...rather than you talking about it I think
showing you visually how this works is probably the most effective so,
the very the most important thing the very first thing is you author a voice
command definition file and you register that with court...
When that's registered with...that effectively becomes part of the
...tasks that court on a knows how to do out-of-the-box so things like hauling and text so,
voice commands something you can author gets registered alongside all of those built-in tasks?
Ok, so, once that's once you're...runs and registers that vc file that was
commend definition file with puerto the...goes away and then.
The user says ...the...now ready to interact with
...so in this case suppose there's a sample application called adventure works at
...provides a capability that to show you upcoming trips so this case the user
says adventure works show my trip to london...takes that.
Statement or utterance passes it to the windows speech platform which is on device
which gets routed up to the cloud comes back to arbitrary what is the user sayings we take advantage of the
cloud and local recognition to help arbitrary what the intent of that of what the
user side was so once we're trying to has that information
and says this is a voice command that's triggered for particular application the
...gets launched or activated essentially with the context so
this particular case the context was I want to show my trip I want to do
with adventure works I want to do it for the particular trip to london.
We're going to look at a lot of demos today that focus on interacting with court author speech one of the things I want to
call...frame for-you up-front is this is very different from doing things
using speech capabilities inside of your application so when you interacting with
this talk is going to focus specifically on how you interact with
...so that the advantages
their the simplicity you get the simplicity the easy access right on the start menu that's what we're going
to talk about today is another talk later this afternoon which is going to talk more
deeply about using speech defying your applications using the speech platform inside of your
apps directly so one of the context up-front for...
Okay, so, that logistical put look at a couple quick demos.
...chat with mark clover using vibe or.
Who is...their and
...started chat with market clover using fiber?
Jeweler starting a chat with mark clover took a second for
her to catch up so if you may have seen this during the keynote session with joe
...what you saw what here as vibrant humming integrated with the core
...experience in this case the context that vibrant defined is they want to
allow users to get into a chat very quickly so ...chat and video
chats in fact so, the idea there the expectation there is that because users have access to
thatcapability really quickly but they're going to be more deeply engaged with...application
providing very quick access to the and expectation...because they have quick access user
based organically can grow using because of...capability so that's a pretty neat one?
Let's look at a different one take...
Starter random game on trivia crack.
Studying random games.
I love this game I'm not sure if you guys play it but it's a really popular
...superfund you may have heard terry talk about it during the keynote as well so.
...max is a company...builds this game they're they took their existing apps
...which was bit built-in html five and convert it to a windows universal lap and...four times
more effective doing so then compared to other native platforms out there and,
because of the time to be the quickness of being able to bring
...windows the role to take advantage of some of the deeper capabilities inside of windows like
proton integration so, the expectation years letting users get into the game much quicker by leveraging
...tunnel users are going to be more deeply engaged that's a
really cool way to get users quickly into the key scenario in the app let's look at a different one.
Started game with to travis wilson using trivia crack.
Studying gain with travis wilson.
Travis...a friend of mine just pulled up his so the that I can put
...start playing with so much and actually going
...show you how quickly it was for me to interact with court on and get into...
I'm not very good arts...going to spare you spare myself embarrassment the context
there that we're passing was I wanted to play game with...the very specific context
...contact I was able to pass that to...tunnel so let's switch
back and take a look at some of the definitions on how you would do that.
...define your own voice.
So, this is an example voice command definition file.
One of the most important things is or I'm sorry
one at the top-level is the command such as the commence that think of it as
it's the container of all commands that you're going to define so in the trivia crack case you saw
me execute two different...to be the container for those to commits most important thing here is this
defines the...the language that you're going to find the commands that contains so in this case we're defining
...commands for the en-us language next up is the
app name so this is what defines how users are going to identify your
application so the recommendation...something very specific that users can remember
that is in fact your app name something directed your brand or...
name something that's very specific to you and your application so,
you can if you have a very long application name like let's suppose you're name is
scape for business two thousand thirteen you can shorten that...and that's
okay but the idea is that something that users can remember...associate with your application?
Example...something that...in the...to give users
...idea of what how they can interact with court...look at what that looks like in a minute?
We get into the really interesting stuff the command,
command is essentially the logical unit of atomic unit really of
the specific thing or intent so, this contains what the user can say
there's some specific syntax for that also contains what core
...can say in response to the user executing that command and what
action portable perform in this case you see the navigate element that effectively as a hint
...to say I want this commands to launch my app with some context?
Once you've authored...authoring...the most important part once you've authored
...you register with the voice command definition manager
and the activate that's how you register with court on alongside all the built-in tasks
and then you override your apps on activated and effectively want to voice command comes in for your
app you get launched
your scenarios launch you get past a name value per collection of the
...specifics...of context that you define in your voice...in your voice command file so
this particular case there is a destination which is part of that context and you'll be
...that destination as a name value...can have other things are others that
name about named parts of this command and this particular case there's just...one but you'd be
past destination as a semantic value that you can then query against to execute document.
So, maybe thinking right now ok that's.
Really neat but how...how it...really that simple like how to how difficult
...to do this so, here's an example voice
command file so this was you know,...we just talk through the command set the app
...actually quickly show you the example text and where that shows up so if I go into protons help
many right here down at the bottom you can see that I have a set of apps registered so if I go
into adventure works show trip to london that's the top-level command set example text
...I can see some of the very specific things I'm able to say to
...so this is a hence of this is a way that user can
...they forget this is how I can they can go in here and take a look at what how they can interact with
So, what I want to show you is how quickly how quick and easy to actually author these...
so let's focus on this area right here what I want to show you is so,
we looked at the listen for and we know that we can do prefix commands where I can
say adventure works show my trip to a particular destination orange
we've introduced one of the biggest...the feedback we've gotten...that's not the most natural way to execute
a command we've introduced a new capabilities to be able free for you to say require
...name we have some a few options here
...show you right now is before after phrase first of all notice that we've integrated
intel's sense to help you author these there's a ton of help as you walk through...one of these inside
of visual studio...I'm going to show you right now is before or after phrase
...this means is the app
name can appear either before so I can say adventure works show my trip to london or I
can say show my trip to london on or using or with adventure works?
Let's compile...
Nothing fancy about this...it's really just to showcase or a sample of that we have this
is available you can download it will provide links afterwards but here's my trip to london and I
have a couple others registered here so now that I've heard used to this command this
require before after let's see what let me try the phrase take autonomy.
Show my trip to london using adventure works.
I'm afraid I couldn't find any events called trip so let me do anything.
Ok, showing trip to london.
...so I was able to use the after phrase which was pretty cool.
Thank you thank you so, what other really...that we've done
...windows ten which is not just the ability to say before or after but I'm going to copy this listen
for and I'm going to actually show you the art
...new capability in addition to this which is?
The ability to say explicitly specified so...syntactic and actually say where
in the command aware in the utterance you want the app name to appear
so in this case actually want to be able to say show my adventure works trip to london that's
probably the most natural way to express that so here's the syntax for doing...
So, basically we have this we did we say this is a
built-in a reference to the app name so...now...part of the command I
...I want explicitly specified to appear this point in the phrase...when commands match this.
This...the...gets activated so let's give that a try.
That's going to register...closely up.
Show my adventure works trip to london.
Showing trip to london.
So, we're pretty excited about that.
What are the other things we're doing and windows ten or any capability
we've enabled is the ability for windows web apps to
...integrate with court tossing may have heard of
racine during the keynote about windows web apps so this is effectively
an application that's built for the web accessible through the browser that you can submit through manifest to
the windows store let's look at an example of that and how that can integrate with court...we've done some work
...to make that possible for those apps to leverage some of the native capabilities of the device?
So, here I have
...application called a group post-its a sample application...me add notes
and I'm accessing this through the through the browser so I can take notes like pick up the kids.
Great knowing special.
...get saved but, we're going to show you that...windows web app as well.
Show my notes using group post.
Notice side-by-side this is the windows
...web application or windows...side-by-side by the with the app the same
...in the browser so what's interesting about this
is the web writing as a windows web
...able to leverage the capabilities of the native device
...showed you can also do something like this.
...note clean the garage using group post.
All right adding clean the garage to group post.
...that both...web out and.
So,...really excited about this because for people that are building windows web
...you already have your existing website you already have, you know,
that you've invested a ton of time and...of energy into building that making at super easy
for you to bring that to the windows platform and we're making it easy for you
to make it to leverage some of the building capabilities with very little effort.
Specifically all you really need to do to enable that for your windows web apps is to drop...
vc file on your website and add a meta tag to the html that points to that
...when...gets pulled out when you're content from the web
get pulled down to the store following this process you the...post will
know that your bd is applicable and...execute you just saw.
We're pretty excited about that...
Okay, so, we've talked about how you can engage your users through deep linking
to your scenarios one of the things I'm really excited talking about today is completing tasks
directly...core tunnels so this is a brand capability...introducing windows type.
So, this includes the ability to have this includes a
set of apis the control task workflow inside of the core tonic canvas.
Is also includes a set of url templates you can use to complete tasks directly inside of that
cameras?
And, it's also includes apis for a speech interactivity model so this is what court on a
...for and...to the user and also what the user can say to
...within the context of that task or within that context of the
completing that task so this is an example showing you the types of things that
you can control so specifically you're able to
...display your app icon you're able to have.
Speech that's...that's said or that's
...bat or that's spoken back to the user input by...on.
Your able to have a set of content tiles which effectively
are your content your images and,
a link to your application if any point
...more comfortable completing this task inside of your application.
Let's look at some demos of that.
Ten more clover I'm having a lot of fun using vibe or.
I can't connect at the...try again a little bit extra overtime take
...clover I'm having a lot of fun using fiber.
Ok, message mark clover on fiber sounds...
Looks like we have some did looks like we have some internet connectivity issues all skip
...that one instead I'll show you a different one.
Creative st for led zeppelin on pandora.
Looking for st.
Rich station do you want.
Do you want to st for led zeppelin rules?
...so, this nation is ready...
Give just a complete that so now I can go into the pandora up.
You see leads up when we're at the top.
So, the idea there this is
...early preview how pandora's thinking about leveraging this capability the idea is...by
...by integrating a
super-high value task for their application directly into the...
on experience they're users can be more effective and more productive so they don't need to context which
when they're already in the middle of doing something thing at that
...and really quickly and get back to what they were doing super valuable scenario.
So, let me try that library scenario one more time just to see how it goes?
Tell...clover I'm having a lot of fun using vibe or.
Ok,
message mark clover on vibe or I'm having a lot of fun sounds good.
Message sent.
So, this is an example of how fibers integrated a high-value task directly into the core tonic
experience.
...click there and there is back into by can vibe...message...
Let's take a look at the architecture and how we make this happen?
Just like before you can author vc file.
Una register that directly with...
That gets registered alongside all of the other tasks the coronas about.
When a user says adventure works show my trip to london but suppose in this case the
...adventure works once that task to be completed in the core
...canvas let's look at how...happens so when the user
says that just like before that speech gets routed to the internal speech platform up to the microsoft
platform speech platform service and back-up...determines that that's a voice command for the
app but this time instead of activating the app in the foreground with context
it's going to communicate with a new concept which is a voice commend background
service so this is like any other background service that runs on windows it actually implements
...up background...background task and you basically implement the run method on that we've added a
set of new apis on top of that you can take advantage?
...the background service...gets the command that service can talk
...our that background task communicate with its own back-end service you
can also talk with local isolated storage and, renders animal so
in the pandora case you saw the round-trip back to that service coming back with results the...that
...displayed onto the canvas.
In this case rather than launch the
...we're showing an icon and some text and some ui back in the back in the screen.
So, one of the...through a little bit of the workflow steps and how what's the what's the anatomy of a task
workflow so you've seen kind of the few examples you've seen or the overall architecture let's zoom in a
little bit suppose someone says cancel my adventure works trip very first stage or the
very first capability we offer through set of apis is the ability to disambiguation amongst
the set of options right so if I say cancel my adventure works trip
...has no idea which...you want to cancel if you have two of them so she can ask just like you saw the
...example with the list of options the first thing you can do is disambiguation
monks a set of options so in this case
adventure works asks which one you want to cancel users can say vegas tech conference one?
The next stage in the workflow is the ability to confirm and operation so if I'm going to cancel trip if
...your cancel trip you want to make pretty sure that's exactly what the user wants to do so this is an
optional part of the workflow where you can confirm and operation so here
...says do you want to cancel this one that I heard you don't hear you correctly you can say yes.
And, then is...it's the progress screens the progress screen is we provide the ability for the
app to provide in progress updates for and
operational tasks that's ongoing so you have a long-running operation something that's going to take some time
...ideal is not to leave the user
waiting so you definitely want to be thinking about the types of interactions are trying to build but
not keep the user weight but in the case in the scenario where you're sure that the product of the
task is going to continue and you're making good progress on it you can provide updates to the user
to tell them and keep them make them feel like they're part of the workflow they know that progress is being made?
The final phase is...completion phase where you display the results...a
few examples of that where you can say this...successful this operation completed successfully.
...spend a little bit of time talking about some of the apis just to give you a feel for the things that are there this is
only sdk that's the that's available today have some great samples
and great documentation...take a look at as well.
The core class here is...service connection to
request a disambiguation screen like you just saw there's a method to do that the request a
confirmation screen same thing requesting...launch to complete the tasks at any point during the workflow we didn't show
...show you this one but at any point during the
workflow you can choose to say I don't want to continue this in the canvas I just want my...to be
launched and let the user complete the task there you can you can request that were prosper trying to do that.
You can also inform...on the status of an in progress task.
And, you can...proton that a task completed successfully or
that fails to complete successfully.
Just want to give you a feel for the types of things that are.
So, you notice the previous on the previous slide voice command response was a
key class the gets return to court...a little bit
of time giving you an idea of the types of things that what that cost contains
now you can use it so the...command response is made up of.
Essentially a encompasses the entire tile or what the entire canvas
...you can control what are the key pieces...the message so the message that you're sending back to
...effectively both the text...gets displayed to the user
...user sees but also contains the speech that core
...speak back to the users lizard...those can be very different things like you don't want to
keep very long thing you want...on the screen you don't want to notice that there are speaking out to the
...a long-time so short...can short form the speech that kind of speaks
...we have a longer string more descriptive string...that you display on...
The next pieces the repeat message we have the repeat message because sometimes you know,
...part-time may not here you the speech recommend have
been not a very high confidence to know for sure that's what the user...those scenarios
...the ability free to provide a repeat message so...a more interactive experience for the user so it's
...krause not just sitting there saying exact same thing over and over again.
you'll notice a list of content tiles the list of content tiles is effectively the core of what you can
draw...the canvas and look at that more detail on a second.
The last thing I want to talk about on the response is the apa launch
argument so again at any point that we built this with the principle...any point of the
users more comfortable completing this task in the app they can launch the apps
...provide a and...launch argument that...on a or
...the user say I want to do this in the app user can tap or user can tap launched
...application with...you...that context just like we saw the depleting scenarios you can provide
context for what you pass so.
In the case of if I was showing my trip to london or I want to cancel it like
that links could be specific directly to my london trip ...you're able to do that.
So, let's look at let's begin on the content tile because this was this is what you're providing back the list of content...to
...so what's, what's the anatomy of that so this is made up of each cut single content
...public title.
It's made up of an optional set of optional text lines which you can provide.
Made up of an icon which you can show on the screen and there's some different template someone go into all the details of the various
...you can use but they're all documented on the web the
...we're going to have a little bit later we'll go into a little bit more depth on this.
There's the...launch arguments were any point of the user clicked the icon or clicked on the
canvas.
The apple get launched with...context and this is how you
...that context that you want to get back to your application of the user taped on that particular tile.
just provide you give a couple examples of type the types of things that you might use this for so,
imagine checking in the user says I want to check in on my place.
Looking for your...in progress screens confirmation screen followed
by a success message or successfully different example might be
changing a budget so I say I want to change my budget to
two hundred-dollars with my budget up confirmation and then a final
...scenarios we've looked at here are consumer
focus to want to point out that we're building this as a platform the scenarios...if
...you're building universal windows apps and the...sense
...for your workflows for your either institution or small business or
large business ...build we built this...a platforms...you take that away this is not just
the consumer focused thing we're building this truly as a platform the...to build on.
Okay, so, we've talked about integrating deep linking to your scenarios from
...we've talked about integrating tasks.
Directly inside a portage the next thing I want to talk about is finding information quickly.
...time so as, you know,...provides pretty effortless expression of search queries I
can type I can you speech to interact with corona pretty simple pretty effortless.
When you're defining things...a very common pattern a very common question for people to have their own
...defined very large data sets that they need to search over it's
...compound with voice commands but, it's a hard problem to solve so,
imagine you're a retailer for shoes and shows
shoes have colors they have sale prices they have different promotions
you're trying to offer how do you search sone user says I'm looking for blue shoes that are less than two
hundred-dollars by the particular manufacture how do you do that effectively quickly you can build voice
commands to do that but the ability to go and searcher database and return or your service and
provide back results effectively and efficiently...this is such a common pattern they want to
spend a little bit of time talking about how you can make that real figures for your service of your apps?
So, consider in this situation integrating your voice commands with
a search back-end service to provide easy quick access
a across those large data stores and return rank results that are relevant to you and
your own business when you asked a question by default you know, not through
...voice command she can you can tap into a vast array of information
that's public but what if you want to use your own small business data or
data specific to your application like in the pandora case it was music results so
...a service you can hit that...results how can you do that is that are the reach of it
most people or how do you do so it turns out that microsoft has a great answer for this we
...a service called as research and, you can...effectively searches a service on the
asher platforms...other service and it's really simple...set-up and
...for steps to...workable...search back-end provision the service on the
actual portal create...index for the data that you want
to serve up load the data into it and...
Through...the...interface for that there's a link their for how you can get started
...a free option for starting experimentation provides
really great building blocks for great search experiences.
Want to show you an example of that.
Trail finder find trails near me.
Here are some trails.
So, what you're seeing here is what
we've loaded in the as research back-end is the united states geographical survey of
features within the united states so actually I'm sorry for the state of california specifically in this
...includes trails mountains hills various features of geographical
object graphical importance so in this case I'm searching for trails and,
...task directly into the canvas which shows me trails that are near me...authorized the
...finder...sample up to access my location
given my location I'm able to show trails that are nearby?
So,...also
shown here the city in which that trail exists and the elevation so this to
this is what you see this number here is the elevation this is all pulled from the publicly available
us gs datasets click on that link.
I'm deep linked into the app mobile to see a map of where that exists where that
trailers...able to see the state the county the class about
trail the elevation and some other things.
Let's look at a different example.
Travel finder find rattlesnake trail.
Here are some trails.
So, in this case...previous example I was searching for things near me using
my geographic location in this case I'm using a keyword
...search directly into my and my search back-end coming back with results that are
ranks their relevant to my experience to my scenario which is finding a trip.
Just like before...showing the city and the elevation of
...of like click.
I can again goin' see...and some of the
other relevant information so this is a really powerful pattern.
Your you leveraging this pattern you're essentially able to quickly search
quickly and you use court on...find information
...against your own private datasets pretty interesting
and if you're interested in this there's a talk later today or I'm sorry on friday by the
...research team I'll give a reference to that a little bit later and, you can you can learn more about how you set up
...search instance and some of the more detailed things that can do.
So, one of the.
Wrap-up by talking about some of the
...we've looked wrap-up by what we've talked about and look at some very specific cost action for what you can go do
today.
...give users quick and easy access to frequently access scenarios in your
app by deep linking to them this helps engage them more deeply in your apps
...so think about those few scenarios that are really quarter application you want them
to get access to and what are those what's that context that you would pass to get them into that
state the second one is hope to users be more productive by enabling them to complete
your apps high-value tasks directly and core tunnel this helps them not have to
context which so frequently so often so again think about those high-value tasks
...want to help them complete directly in the core tonic canvas leverage the set of apis were offering today?
The third one as enabler users to access important information by connecting
your voice commands to a back-end service that supports efficient search over your data so I showed you the
adverse search example that's an easy one to get set up that's one we have at microsoft you can build your own
there's a ton of other there's no by no means is this specific what I showed you to
...research you can connect...search terms to any search back-end or any
database reservist that's comfortable for you that you're familiar with that you want to use to serve up information
...provides that really efficient and easy to access model right
on the windows caspar for users to get access to information so consider how you would
help your users of your application access that information quickly.
Complete the hands-on quick start challenges while you're here we have a couple great
ones this will give you hands-on experience with implementing a lot of what you just saw here.
And, download the samples...have access to this...linked the adventure work sample
which you just saw there's also the group post windows web app which you can download and,...track finder
...we...available for windows phone eight-point one-quarter...coming soon we're going to release that pretty soon for windows ten.
And, read the...documents for walking you through these things and helping you
get started ...commands we spend a lot of time on speech interactions in your app this is
the topic we're going to covering the six thirty session right in this room...bit like a
...later today this is what I was referring to earlier which is about enabling
your...speech inside of your applications and then third visit the bing
developer center some really great features we're introducing to enable so,
today these capabilities allow your application
to be served up during search results on...dot com and,
deep linked into the app through search results on the web that's a capability that
we're looking to introduced during the windows ten timeframe to core tunnel.
So, there's a lot more a...great information on that on the thing developer center.
And,...here I need to...talks related to this one so first
...indep session on what I was talking about the goes a lot more depth on the how would you build this her
have some of the implementation details will also go into the details of the
speech platform apis you can use inside of your app that's right here at six thirty so take a break come
Building with bing so this is a session that's going to go very deep on the...linking scenarios...
was just mentioning this is going to talk specifically through the web about the web but they're going to touch on the
...stuff as well so makes make sure...that's an area of interest being discover discovered through
...how your
actions in your applications can get discover through search queries so they can appear in court
...definitely take a look at that the specific focus of
was saying this is going to be available the windows ten timeframe there's a few segments that are support that
this capabilities...support initially which is...movies and,
books so if you are in the idea is that over time
that sort of domains that this applicant concept support is going to grow so,
definitely check that out if that's of...you being more discoverable through core...through the web.
The third one is tomorrow as research public
castro excellent speaker wonderful person he
...was going to go super deep on the...research service.
Posted web apps and web app platform this talk already has happened but,
I've listed...to be recorded so you can access this at a later time.
And, finally the altering session which is already happened this is we there is an example of accord
...integration for home automation scenario so that's another way you can leverage these ways
...home automation scenarios again,
this session is already happened but you can be sure to check that out all the
recorded session deceit...kind ofhow that would working what they've done to use all join connected...
All right and...that would love for you to evaluate the session and provide
your feedback and we're going to take cue in a and then after the sessions we're going-to be heading
over to the windows insiders lounge both an eye and other members of the team so if you have any questions
would like some more than happy to talk and, have deeper conversation about things?